Sam Gates

Sam.J.Gates@gmail.com | 919-815-0639 | Raleigh, North Carolina 27615

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/3tRs1ws | GitHub: https://github.com/sg0703 | Portfolio: https://samgates.io/

SUMMARY

Web Developer currently completing a certificate program in Full Stack Web Development at University of North Carolina. Started coding around age eleven, self-taught with HTML, CSS, PHP and MySQL. After many years in public service, I am returning to my dream of being a professional web developer. Possess a strong work ethic and a dedication to learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, REST API's, Sass, React.js

Backend: Node, Express, MySQL, PHP

PROJECTS

Employee Tracker | Repo: https://bit.ly/3xFfZJ0 | Video: https://bit.ly/2R7f6rz | Role: Creator

Summary: Node Employee Tracker is a Node.js command line app that allows a user to manage a MySQL database

of employees, managers, roles, and departments. Written using object oriented programming.

Tools: JavaScript, Node.js, Inquirer, Util, and MySQL.

Team Profile Generator | Repo: https://bit.ly/3ngMzvV | Role: Creator

Summary: Node.js command line application. Quickly and easily generate a team web page for your next project!

Built using Object Oriented Programming practices. **Tools:** JavaScript, Node.js, Inquirer, HTML, and CSS.

Weather App! | Repo: https://bit.ly/3aKxm15 | Deployed: https://bit.ly/2R8ZNPu | Role: Creator

Summary: Weather App! utilizes the OpenWeather API to search for a specific city and return weather data,

including a 5 day forecast, for that city.

Tools: OpenWeather API, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Moment.js, HTML, and CSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coldwell Banker HPW

Real Estate Broker

Nov. 2020 - March 2021

Raleigh, North Carolina

- Self employed, generated leads and marketed business
- Provided outstanding customer service and advice to clients
- Expertly negotiated with other agents and vendors

Raleigh Police Department

Senior Officer

Jan. 2012 - Oct. 2020

Raleigh, North Carolina

- Served as a patrol officer with Raleigh PD for almost 9 years, achieved the rank of Senior Officer
- Worked closely with the public on a daily basis
- Responded to 911 calls of all types
- Conducted interviews, carried out investigations, wrote reports, preserved evidence, appeared and testified in court
- Developed and utilized universal skills, such as leading a team, communicating effectively with members of the public, completing tasks under pressure, and employing an unbreakable work ethic
- Earned Lifesaving Award and received numerous Letters of Commendation

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Coding Boot Camp, North Carolina July 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in full stack web development. Curriculum includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Handelbars.js, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Heroku, Git, and API's.

North Carolina State University

August 2010

Bachelor of Arts in German Studies, Summa Cum Laude